<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Machine Learning - Category - Sumit Yadav</title>
        <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/categories/machine-learning/</link>
        <description>Machine Learning - Category - Sumit Yadav</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>rockerritesh4@gmail.com (rockerritesh)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>rockerritesh4@gmail.com (rockerritesh)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:50:41 &#43;0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sumityadav.com.np/categories/machine-learning/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Multi_Class_Text_Classification</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/text_classification/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:50:41 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/text_classification/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Multi_Class_Text_Classification This post and code are used in a challenge organized by LOCUS called DataRush.
Hi!, Today in this post i am going to share our effort which was applied by us in a competition organized by LOCUS.
Lets start, for this challenge we have give data sets which contain a train data csv which contain four columns and 390603 rows ie 390603 rows × 4 columns. As in each row we have given &lsquo;id&rsquo; number( which is random id number to represent id), &lsquo;abstract&rsquo; which contain main part for this competition which we have to classify.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Nepali_OCR_Python</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/nepali_ocr/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 12:02:51 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/nepali_ocr/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Nepali OCR detector In this post I am going to present Nepali Optical Character Recognition (OCR) that extracts Nepali text from images and scanned documents so that it can be edited, formatted, indexed, searched, or translated. Below mentioned code are written in python, using easyocr as a heart of this post.
OCR Optical character recognition or optical character reader (OCR) is the electronic or mechanical conversion of images of typed, handwritten or printed text into machine-encoded text, whether from a scanned document, a photo of a document, a scene-photo (for example the text on signs and billboards in a landscape photo) or from subtitle text superimposed on an image (for example: from a television broadcast).]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>AutoEncoder</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/autoencoder/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 20:05:33 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/autoencoder/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[AUTO ENCODER In this notebook you will find how auto encoder are trained in tensorflow(Keras). This notebook have two different type of encoder i.e normal * Auto Encoder * and * Denoising Auto Encoder * . Normal Encoder LIBRARY ARE LOADED
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 %matplotlib inline %config InlineBackend.figure_format = &#39;retina&#39; import matplotlib.pyplot as plt import pandas as pd import numpy as np import seaborn as sns import warnings warnings.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Unsupervised</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/supervised/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 13:52:07 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/supervised/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[VAE VAE TYPES
Auto Encoder This is like a simple generative algorithm in which one model is used to reduce the data like simple compression and other is for increasing data like decompressor. This model contain different neural network model for both of task. Here there is difficult to develop or generate determined image from compressed laten space. Variational Autoencoders Up to now, we have discussed dimensionality reduction problem and introduce autoencoders that are encoder-decoder architectures that can be trained by gradient descent.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Nepali_Devanagari_Letter_Classifier</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/first_post/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/first_post/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In the search of deep data analytic we comes to deep machine learnig which is most famous way of finding pattern in data and predicting the future state of data pattern.
In this python based machine learning code i have written a convolution based deep learnig code of predicting and recogination of number,letter and and many more. In this code i have used tranfer learning way of predicting number and letter in real time by using c++ based one of the famous visual modulus callled Open CV.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
