<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - Sumit Yadav</title>
        <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | Sumit Yadav</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>rockerritesh4@gmail.com (rockerritesh)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>rockerritesh4@gmail.com (rockerritesh)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 08:53:14 &#43;0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://sumityadav.com.np/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Mahadev</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/mahadev/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 08:53:14 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/mahadev/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In a village, Shiva ruled as the king and held sway over his kingdom. However, over time, two influential individuals arrived from another land. They were known as Vishnu and Brahma, each having their own kingdom in their homeland. These newcomers quickly earned a reputation in the village as powerful kings.
As time passed, the three rulers contemplated the idea of determining who among them would be considered the &ldquo;Mahadevta&rdquo; or &ldquo;Mahadev,&rdquo; a significant title often associated with Lord Shiva.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Jur Shital: A Celebration of Water and Life in Mithila</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/jur_shital/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 06:07:21 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/jur_shital/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Jur Shital is a vibrant and colorful festival celebrated by the people of Mithila region, which comprises parts of India and Nepal. This festival is celebrated on the 2nd of Baisakh, the second month of the Hindu calendar. Jur Shital is a festival that celebrates water and life, and it is a time when people come together to pray for good health, prosperity, and longevity.
One of the most interesting aspects of Jur Shital is the tradition of watering the head of the younger members of the family.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Functional dependency</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/functional-dependency/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 18:07:21 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/functional-dependency/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Functional dependency explained. You Functional dependency
ChatGPT In the context of relational databases, a functional dependency is a relationship between two or more attributes (or columns) in a table where the value of one attribute determines the value of another.
For example, if we have a table called &ldquo;Students&rdquo; with the columns &ldquo;Student_ID,&rdquo; &ldquo;First_Name,&rdquo; &ldquo;Last_Name,&rdquo; and &ldquo;Email,&rdquo; we can say that the attribute &ldquo;Email&rdquo; is functionally dependent on the attributes &ldquo;First_Name&rdquo; and &ldquo;Last_Name.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Operating_System</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/operating_system/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 18:07:21 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/operating_system/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[OPerating system and function
1 / 1
An operating system (OS) is a software system that manages computer hardware and software resources and provides common services for computer programs. The main functions of an operating system include:
Process management: The OS manages the execution of computer programs, called processes, by allocating system resources such as memory, CPU time, and input/output devices.
Memory management: The OS manages the allocation and deallocation of memory resources to processes, ensuring that each process has the necessary memory to execute.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Query optimization</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/queryoptimizationtechniques/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 18:07:21 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/queryoptimizationtechniques/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Query optimization techniques. You query peocessing and optimization
ChatGPT Query processing and optimization are two important aspects of database management systems that deal with the execution of user queries on a database.
Query processing involves transforming a user query written in a high-level language (such as SQL) into a series of lower-level operations that can be executed by the database system. The process of query processing typically involves parsing the query, checking it for syntactic and semantic errors, optimizing the query execution plan, and executing the query to retrieve the desired data.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Mathili_Script</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/ioe_bachelors_ai_project_pulchowk_campus/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 18:07:21 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/ioe_bachelors_ai_project_pulchowk_campus/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[TRIBHUVAN UNIVERSITY INSTITUTE OF ENGINEERING PULCHOWK CAMPUS
Machine Learning Analysis of Tirhuta Lipi
By:
Sumit Yadav (076/BCT/088) Raju Kumar Yadav (076/BCT/100) Prashant Bhandari (076/BCT/049)
AN AI PROJECT REPORT TO THE DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING.
DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING LALITPUR, NEPAL
March, 2023
ii
ACKNOWLEDGEMENT
This project is prepared in partial fulfilment of the requirement for for the the bachelor’s degree in Electronics and Communication Engineering. First and foremost, We would also like to extend our sincere thanks to our passout seniors, friends, and family for their support and guidance throughout our research project.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Mithila_festivals</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/mithila_festivals/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 07:47:26 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/mithila_festivals/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Here in this post you will find different festivals, that are celebrated in the region of Mithila (side of Nepal janakpur, tirhut, and parts of Bihar). Mithila festivals is very much hidden from rest of the worlds. As mentioned in ramayan, every day in mithila is a day of new festival and tradition.
They are Lets go with day in weeks.
Sunday &mdash;&gt; Raib Fasting Monday &mdash;&gt; Sombarii Tuesday &mdash;&gt; Mangal Bari Thursday &mdash;&gt; Bairaspat Bari Friday &mdash;&gt; Sukra Bari Saturday &mdash;&gt; Jai Hanuman Sunday.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Tensor_processing_units</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/tensor_processing_units/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:07:21 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/tensor_processing_units/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Sumit Yadav&nbsp;(PUL076BCT088)
Prof. Dr. &nbsp;Subarna Shakya&nbsp;
Director, Information Technology Innovation Center, Tribhuvan University
Computer Organization and Architecture
09&nbsp;June&nbsp;2022
TPUs (Tensor Processing Unit)
Tensor Processing Units (TPUs) are custom-designed application-specific integrated circuits (ASICs) developed by Google to accelerate AI &nbsp;and neural network works. Formally, it was begun in 2015 and first made available publicly &nbsp;in 2018 for both cloud computing and small business. Tensor processing unit was first introduced in 2016 at Google I/O, when the company said the TPU had been already used in the company for over a year.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Multi_Class_Text_Classification</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/text_classification/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:50:41 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/text_classification/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Multi_Class_Text_Classification This post and code are used in a challenge organized by LOCUS called DataRush.
Hi!, Today in this post i am going to share our effort which was applied by us in a competition organized by LOCUS.
Lets start, for this challenge we have give data sets which contain a train data csv which contain four columns and 390603 rows ie 390603 rows × 4 columns. As in each row we have given &lsquo;id&rsquo; number( which is random id number to represent id), &lsquo;abstract&rsquo; which contain main part for this competition which we have to classify.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Drum</title>
    <link>http://sumityadav.com.np/drum/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 10:27:05 &#43;0545</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>http://sumityadav.com.np/drum/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ A clap S hihat D kick F openhat G boom H ride J snare K tom L tink ]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
